<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Bo Peng</title>
 <link href="bopeng.io//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="bopeng.io/"/>
 <updated>2015-06-21T02:46:07-04:00</updated>
 <id>bopeng.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Bo Peng</name>
   <email>me@bopeng.io</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>My Enactus Nationals Experience</title>
   <link href="bopeng.io///my-enactus-nationals-experience"/>
   <updated>2015-05-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>bopeng.io/my-enactus-nationals-experience</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What a difference a year makes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/enactus-cover.png&quot; alt=&quot;Enactus Cover&quot; /&gt;
One year ago today I was counting down the days until high school graduation. Suffering from boredom and “senioritis”, I did my usual thing and scrolled through Facebook, hoping to find something remotely interesting. Fifteen minutes later, I managed to come across this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oPW25D0WQy8&quot;&gt;video.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was probably thinking at the time “Interesting… A 23 minute long video with the title Enactus National Champions. What does Enactus even mean? There’s no chance my attention span is going to last for more than 5 minutes watching this.” Little did I know this video was going to change my life. Anyways, I watched the first few minutes of the presentation and was instantly hooked to their passion and projects. If you haven’t watched Enactus Ryerson’s presentation yet, I would strongly recommend it. I will personally guarantee two things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;You will be inspired.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The line “turning ideas into reality” will get stuck in your head.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After hearing “turning ideas into reality” a gazillion times, I had an idea: I wanted to start an Enactus team at the University of Waterloo and change the world just like Enactus Ryerson. It wasn’t easy, but Enactus Waterloo officially joined the Enactus family in November 2014. My idea would not have turned into reality without the support of Annie Chen (other co-founder), Julie Marin (our lovely program manager), and David Rose (faculty advisor).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team recently attended the Enactus Canada National Competition in downtown Toronto. It was truly an incredible and empowering three day experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/enactus-presentation-team.png&quot; alt=&quot;Enactus Presentation Team&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day consisted mainly of registration, meetings, and the opening ceremonies. The opening ceremony was pretty damn epic. I’ve never seen that much spirit and passion contained in a single room. We witnessed the first presentation of Enactus Nationals, presented proudly by the Enactus Canada head office team. Simply put, it was informational and quite humorous. Next up, Ricardo Martin, Vice President of Marketing of Unilever Canada, delivered a  wonderful, humbling keynote speech. I was also fortunate enough to be the recipient of Enactus Canada’s Rising Star award. Although winning this award was sweet, the highlight of my night was watching Acacia (from Enactus Thompson Rivers) win the HSBC Woman Leader of Tomorrow Award.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, I woke up bright and early at 5:00AM, so I could commute from Vaughan to Toronto and attend the 7:00AM tech checks. Our entire presentation team actually commuted from home, since we wanted to save some money. Abhishek, Amy, Annie, and Nirupan made up the presentation team, and I was on tech. Overall, I thought our presentation team did a great job. Later in the day, I found some time to watch a few of the National Challenges presentations. I particularly enjoyed Enactus Ottawa’s soccer officiating program and Enactus St. Mary’s University’s Start Up 100 project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/enactus-early-morning.png&quot; alt=&quot;Enactus Early Morning&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, it was the moment everyone was waiting for. Brett Wilson’s awesome talk. His speech had everything you expected a great speech would have and much more. The most powerful part of his talk was when someone asked “Who do you look up to in life?” He initially responded with a very influential Canadian businessman (name which I sadly can not remember). He thought about it a bit more and then changed his answer to “someone who spends time with their children and family.” This response left me in deep thought for quite a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/enactus-brett.png&quot; alt=&quot;Enactus Brett Wilson&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuesday night concluded with the announcement of the winners from the opening round. We were in the last league, so it took a while before the results from our league was announced. The play-by-play went something like this. The spirit award goes to Western, the runner-up goes to SFU, and the semi-finalists are… the University of Waterloo and Wilfrid Laurier University! Just wow. I couldn’t believe it, though at the same time, I knew we did the best we could do. Having our neighbours and friends Enactus Laurier move on with us made the moment even more memorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only downside was the fact that one of our members flew back to Korea after our first presentation. As you might guess, this led to some obvious problems. That night, I had to memorize her entire set of lines and then present the next morning. Needless to say, it was an interesting and stressful experience, especially when you’re not staying overnight at the hotel. We presented and once again, I thought our presentation went very well. Unfortunately, this time we did not move on to the finals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/enactus-laurier-team.png&quot; alt=&quot;Enactus Laurier Team&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four finalists were University of Ottawa, St. Lawrence College, St. Mary’s University, and University of Windsor. The four teams were all well deserving finalists and they all had fantastic presentations and projects. Several announcements later, Enactus Ottawa was chosen as the National Champions, with Enactus St. Mary’s winning runner-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was invited to the Reception of Champions, which may have been the best part of my first Enactus Nationals experience. I had the opportunity to meet many of Enactus Ottawa’s dedicated members and learn from their experiences. I also had the chance to talk with members and faculty from exceptional Enactus programs: Lambton College, Ryerson University, University of Windsor, St. Mary’s University, and St. Lawrence College. I learned from a conversation with Ian Aitken (Founder and Chair of Enactus Canada) that he and Preston weren’t related. He also noted that in other Enactus Nationals, the two finalists are actually led on to the stage and then the winner is selected in a American Idol fashion. Finally, I met David Primmer, the donor of Enactus Rising Star Award. Awesome guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, this was quite a long blog post. I’ve never been more inspired and I’m ready to take our Enactus Waterloo program to the next level. This is going to be one incredible year.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Five Important Life Qualities</title>
   <link href="bopeng.io///five-important-life-qualities"/>
   <updated>2015-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>bopeng.io/five-important-life-qualities</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-be-a-dick&quot;&gt;1. Don’t be a dick.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, this is the most important rule in life. Some people may know this phrase as the Golden Rule: &lt;strong&gt;“Treat others how you’d like to be treated.”&lt;/strong&gt; There’s a good reason why this expression appears everywhere, whether it’s your parents teaching you about manners, or as seen in religious texts. Respect others and be considerate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is actually the easiest lesson to follow, but it astonishes me how many people in this world don’t know the meaning of respect. I plead for you to praise this rule because nobody wants to work with a disrespectful individual in academic or professional environments. &lt;em&gt;Hint&lt;/em&gt; In job interviews, employers assess both your technical skills and fit with the company culture. For example, you could be the best software developer in the world, but if the employer doesn’t want to work with you, then you’re not getting the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In job interviews, employers assess both your technical skills and fit with the company culture. For example, you could be the best software developer in the world, but if the employer doesn’t want to work with you, then you’re not getting the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;good-isnt-good-enough&quot;&gt;2. Good isn’t good enough.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I mean by this expression is that there is always space for improvement. Even when you think you did a great job, the truth is you can do even better. You should always be aiming to improve yourself. Try to learn something new every day or go into depth of something you previous knew. If you settle with where you’re at right now, then you’re going to plateau and never grow as an individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re making important career decisions, you should ask yourself the following questions “What will I learn from this experience? Will it make me (or my business) better?” It’s also important to note that competing with others is an awesome motivator to improve; however, your most important goal should be to be better than the person you were yesterday. This is the reason why I love the start-up culture so much. If a start-up doesn’t move fast enough, then it won’t reach its targets or perhaps even get destroyed by its competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shit-happens-it-gets-better&quot;&gt;3. Shit happens, it gets better.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excuse my language in this blog post, but the &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/D_Vg4uyYwEk?t=97&quot;&gt;world ain’t all sunshine and rainbows.&lt;/a&gt; Life isn’t fair, shit happens. You could be the nicest person in the world, but there are certain things in life which you can’t control. Bad things are going to happen to you some point in life, and you’ll be in the wrong place at the wrong time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must accept failure and unfortunate events as an inevitable part of life. Rather than complaining about how terrible your life is, accept it and move on. Complaining will only drag you behind and waste your time. Don’t drink your sorrows away or wait for that lucky moment. &lt;em&gt;It’s probably not going to happen.&lt;/em&gt; You’re going to have to work hard and put in the time to make things better. It won’t be easy. Just remember that life will get better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;surround-yourself-with-good-company&quot;&gt;4. Surround yourself with good company.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, the environment you’re in shapes your past, present and future. Every individual who you interact with affects your life in some way. You have the power to choose the people you want in your life (obviously parents and guardians are exceptions). There are going to be people who push you towards success and then there are going to be people who do the exact opposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in an environment where you are not happy or learning from the people around you, then you should reconsider your options. Surround yourself with good company and make sure you’re with people who can help you prosper and reach your full potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;have-fun-enjoy-life&quot;&gt;5. Have fun, enjoy life.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but definitely not least, have fun! I’m not going to write about this subject because you can figure it out by yourself. Live your life and enjoy the ride!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Applying to Your First Co-op Job</title>
   <link href="bopeng.io///applying-to-your-first-coop-job"/>
   <updated>2015-03-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>bopeng.io/applying-to-your-first-coop-job</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hey world! It’s been a long time since I last posted. I apologize for this delay, but I’ve never been so busy in my life. I can’t believe that first year is going to be over in one month from now. Time flies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’ll be going over my experience applying to my first co-op job and providing tips to maximize your chances. This blog post will be tailored towards engineering and math students, though students of all faculties can benefit from reading this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/jobmine-cover.png&quot; alt=&quot;co-op&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1-gather-relevant-experiences-and-projects&quot;&gt;Step 1: Gather relevant experiences and projects.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I mean by this step is to actually do stuff and have content to put on your resume. Getting a job in a field related to your major would be awesome to include on your resume. However, this isn’t realistic for the majority of people, so another approach is to get involved in extracurriculars and student design teams. I would recommend checking out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feds.ca/clubs-section/clubs-listing/&quot;&gt;Federation of Students clubs&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://uwaterloo.ca/sedra-student-design-centre/directory-teams&quot;&gt;engineering student design teams.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, Bridges to Prosperity provides civil engineering students with a relevant and enriching experience related to their major. The UW Robotics Team is an awesome opportunity to get involved with robotics. The UW Designed Nanoscale Assembly Team focuses on designing applicable biomedical and nanotechnology innovations for applications such as medicine. Joining clubs not only improve your resume, but they’re also incredibly fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-2-craft-the-best-resume-ever&quot;&gt;Step 2: Craft the best resume ever.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’ve gathered all the content to stuff your resume with, you can focus on the most important step. I won’t go over how to write a resume, since there are numerous guides online. From what I’ve noticed, the best resumes  have the following characteristics: one pager, clean, concise and visually appealing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a great resume is critical in landing that first co-op job, since it’s  the only thing employers can evaluate you by. The first draft of your resume probably will be quite different from the final copy you submit on Jobmine. It is absolutely crucial to receive feedback on your resume and get it critiqued by others. In September, I thought my resume was great, but clearly that was not the case after the upper-years destroyed my resume with red ink. Also, only write a cover letter if you can write a great non-generic one. Remember that crafting the perfect resume is an ongoing process and improvements can always be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-3-apply-to-jobs-on-jobmine&quot;&gt;Step 3: Apply to jobs on Jobmine.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your co-op stream, the job application process begins in early September (stream 4), January (stream 8), or May (sequence 4 math students). On the second Saturday of the academic term, job postings open up on Jobmine. You upload your resume on Jobmine and then apply to jobs on the portal. Applying to jobs is as simple as uploading your resume, and submitting your application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most programs, there are usually hundreds of job listings on Jobmine.
In the first round, you have 50 job applications. This might seem like a lot, but it’s actually not. The first round of application closes the following Tuesday night. The second round of job postings opens up the next week and closes a few days later. My personal advice is to use 40-45 apps during the first round and the remaining apps for the second round because the jobs in the second round tend to be not as great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that you’re not limited to jobs on Jobmine. If you find a job that fascinates you outside of Jobmine, go ahead and apply to them! Several of my friends did this and have had success. For programs where there is a low supply of jobs, I would strongly recommend considering this route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-4-nail-your-interviews&quot;&gt;Step 4: Nail your interviews.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interviews may start as early as the fourth Monday of the term and end on the eighth Thursday of the term. They may either be in person, Skype, or on the phone. All interviews will take place at the Tatham centre, unless otherwise specified. For the majority of the jobs, employers will only conduct one interview. Some employers may send you a coding challenge to do online or in person to determine if you’re fit for another interview. For the U.S. jobs, you can pretty much expect a multistage interview process. In general, interviews are typically around 30 minutes long, though they can range anywhere from 15 minutes to an hour. For technical interview preparation, I would recommend ‘Cracking the Coding Interview’ by Gayle McDowell. Another helpful resource is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hackerrank.com/&quot;&gt;HackerRank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my personal experience with interviews, I’ve noticed a general structure. In the first 5 minutes, you usually introduce yourself and tell them a little about yourself, your passions and the technologies you’ve worked with. Then, the employer will talk about their own company for the next 5-10 minutes. Next up is the technical interview questions, spanning roughly 15-20 minutes. This could be a straight up coding or a “how would you solve this” question. Or, it could be a review of your resume, and asking you specific questions about your experiences and projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For non-coding interviews, the 15-20 minute portion of the interview is mainly behavioural questions. A sample question could be “tell me about your experience and proficiency working with AutoCAD”. The employer usually asks type of questions to determine if you’re a good problem solver and to assess if you’re a right fit for the team. Finally, the interview concludes with you asking questions to the employer. Always come up with one or two good questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key tip for interviews is be confident and don’t think of the interview as “OMG will they accept me?” Instead, think of the interview as a more formal conversation with your future coworkers. They selected you for an interview for a reason, don’t undersell yourself. Interviewers aren’t trying to make your life miserable by giving you hard questions, they’re just looking for someone they can work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-5-rankings&quot;&gt;Step 5: Rankings.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, by this point, you’ve had a couple of interviews and walked out of them happy. On the eighth Friday of the term, rankings open up. The three possibilities are: offer, ranked, or not ranked. If it’s an offer, congratulations! If it’s ‘not ranked’, that means the employer did not select you. If your status is ‘ranked’, then that means the employer wanted you, but you were not their top ranked applicant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have until the following Monday morning to submit your rankings. You can rank the employers anywhere between 1 to 9, with ranking 1 meaning you want them. To secure a job offer, simply rank ‘1’ to the employer that gave you an offer. Give the other employers ranks that are not a ‘1’. If you weren’t ranked for any jobs, then you’re out of luck and will have to go to the continuous round. If you were ranked for jobs, then you’ll have to decide and strategize how to rank them. Note that it is possible to get matched with a job even if you ranked them a 9, so apply to jobs carefully. You do not want to be matched up with a job that you don’t want (it creates a lot of problems).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-6-job-matching&quot;&gt;Step 6: Job matching.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jobmine will apply an algorithm to determine how the rankings will be dealt with. To read more about the specific details, please read &lt;a href=&quot;https://uwaterloo.ca/co-operative-education/get-hired/ranking-matching&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; by CECA. You will find out on the Monday afternoon which job you were matched to. If you got matched with a job, then this is the end of the guide for you. Congratulations, I hope you enjoy your first co-op experience. If you still don’t have a job, then proceed to Step 7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-7-continuous-round&quot;&gt;Step 7: Continuous round.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The continuous round begins the ninth Wednesday of the term and goes on until you have successfully found a job. Don’t be shocked or saddened if you have to go to the continuous round. In fact, only about one third of the students in Engineering and Mathematics are employed after the first round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The continuous round functions pretty much the same way as the first round. You apply to jobs and do the typical interviews. The only twist is that rankings come out every Tuesday and Thursday night, rather than just once during the first round. Matches come out Wednesday and Friday mornings, so hopefully you have been matched up with a job by now. If not, don’t give up and keep on persevering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you happen to be without a job after the first month of the co-op term, it’s not the end of the world. You still have 4 more weeks to find a job. Even if you don’t, you can use the time to focus on self improvement and gather relevant experience and projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-personal-experience-and-thoughts&quot;&gt;My personal experience and thoughts.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My experience with Jobmine has been exactly what I expected from the start: a lot of fun and stress. I worked on personal projects and did most of the things I mentioned in Step 1. I developed the first draft of my resume in September 2014, and continued improving it, until I was finally satisfied. I submitted ‘BoPengResumeV6.pdf’ to Jobmine on Saturday January 17th, 2015 and proceeded to Step 3. I had a very ambitious mindset, applying to several jobs in California and most of senior level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first round, I received 3 interviews. The first was for a large company in Seattle, though admittedly I got wrecked in the phone interview. The second was an established company based in Waterloo. The competition for this job was tough and I was not as prepared for the interviews as I should have been. My last interview was for another senior level job in Waterloo, where I was competing with upper-year students with multiple co-op experiences under their belt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not ranked by all three employers which made me feel a bit sad. My upper-year friends advised me that the continuous round would an amazing opportunity for me, so I was quite optimistic about the future. I revamped to a new, cleaner, more elegant design. Then, I uploaded ‘BoPengResumeV7.pdf’ on Jobmine on March 4th, 2015 and applied to about 130 more jobs. The next thing you know, I get several interviews during the first week alone. I am pleased to announce that I will be working at Bidvine as a Software Developer for the Spring 2015 term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude, getting that first co-op job is not an easy task. As I’m writing this post, most programs currently have employment rates of less than 50%. However, the SE class last year had a final employment rate of 99.3%. What this means is that most students will find a job in the next few weeks. The entire co-op application process is not as pretty as advertised and many students struggle to find suitable jobs. If you follow my advice, then you can optimize your chances of getting that first co-op job.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to Write a Great AIF</title>
   <link href="bopeng.io///how-to-write-a-great-aif"/>
   <updated>2014-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>bopeng.io/how-to-write-a-great-aif</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For most programs at Waterloo, it is strongly recommended to fill out the admission information form (AIF). By the end of this post, you guys will learn how the AIF may be the difference between an offer and rejection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/aif-cover.png&quot; alt=&quot;aif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-story&quot;&gt;My Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I applied to Waterloo and submitted my AIF exactly one year ago. Two months later, I received an offer to my top ranked program in the “early” round of Waterloo Engineering offers. In this round, about 30% of the offers were handed out and Software Engineering applicants had averages of mid-high 90’s. For example, one of my friends had a 97% average, but did not receive an early offer. Although my average was 3-4% lower than his, I was admitted into the program. This example just shows how important the AIF can be. A few months later, I was awarded a Waterloo Faculty of Engineering scholarship, on the basis of strong grades and AIF. Had I not spent so much time and effort on my AIF, I probably wouldn’t have received an early offer or an additional scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just take a look at the graph below (taken from Professor Bill Anderson’s blog). Over 1300 applicants with 90% average were not offered admission. In an age where applicants all have excellent grades, writing a great AIF is the best way to differentiate yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/aif-unadmitted.png&quot; alt=&quot;aif unadmitted&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now, you guys are probably convinced that the AIF is crucial for a successful application. I’ll briefly go over the components of the AIF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;components-of-the-aif&quot;&gt;Components of the AIF&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will have to fill out the first three sections of the AIF and any additional sections required by the program you’re applying to. Engineering students have to fill out the Engineering section and Math students have to fill out the Math section. If you’re applying to multiple programs at Waterloo, you only need to complete one AIF. You can view screenshots of the AIF &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/gyI9T5&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part A:&lt;/strong&gt; You write a short essay response about why you’re applying to Waterloo and why you’re interested in your specific programs. It has a 900 character limit, which is about 140 words. In addition, you list your extracurricular activities (with an optional section to further explain what you did), employment and volunteer history, and past accomplishments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part B:&lt;/strong&gt; This is where you talk about any special circumstances which may have affected your academic performance (note: this is optional). There’s also space at the bottom to add any additional information about yourself. Most people choose to leave this question blank. For myself, I talked about my shadow day experience at Waterloo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part C:&lt;/strong&gt; Basically fill in information about your courses and grades. If you’ve taken courses outside of your day school such as in night school, summer school, online, or a private school, you’ll have to provide a reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engineering Section:&lt;/strong&gt; The first question asks you to write about your Engineering interests and goals, and the second question asks you to write about a book you particularly enjoyed. If you have applied to Software Engineering or you have listed it as an alternate, you’re required to write about your programming experience. Note: taking a high school programming course is sufficient. If you’re interested in being considered for an Engineering scholarship, tick off the box. Finally, you can list up to two alternate Engineering programs. For more information about alternate offers, read &lt;a href=&quot;https://profbillanderson.wordpress.com/2014/05/08/considering-an-alternate-offer-2014/&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Math Section:&lt;/strong&gt; The math section is focused on your past and future math and computing contest scores. It also asks for reference information from a Senior mathematics teacher. As the website states, your teacher does not have to do anything at this time, but may be contacted by admissions personnel to provide a reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aif-grading&quot;&gt;AIF Grading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Bill Anderson wrote about the process and scoring of the AIF, so check out his post &lt;a href=&quot;https://profbillanderson.wordpress.com/2014/01/04/scoring-your-aif/&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tips--strategy&quot;&gt;Tips &amp;amp; Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Before writing the AIF&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Research about the University of Waterloo and your program.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attend the open houses and outreach events (see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://uwaterloo.ca/engineering-student-ambassadors/shadow-program&quot;&gt;Shadow Day program&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk to your teachers, current Waterloo students, and alumni.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compile a list of all your activities and accomplishments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;While writing the AIF&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write personal responses.&lt;/strong&gt; Last year alone, there were 10,000 AIF’s to be read by the Faculty of Engineering. If you write something generic, your application will be just like the others. Pretend you receive a Christmas card from someone. Would you be more impressed if it said “Happy holidays, hope you had a great year!” or if it included something personal like “I’m so glad to have met you this year. Remember that time when we went skating together… Good times.” Demonstrate to the reader that you have put in a lot of thought and effort in writing a personal response. Don’t be generic.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be passionate and genuine.&lt;/strong&gt; Explain to the reader why you want to study at Waterloo so badly. What makes you so passionate about the University of Waterloo? For me, it was the boundless opportunities to grow and learn. If you’ve done extracurricular activities outside of school, make sure that you highlight them and show off how passionate you are. For the reading interest question, choose something that you really enjoyed. It doesn’t necessarily have to be engineering related. Trust me on this one, AIF readers enjoy reading about passionate people. Of course, be genuine in your responses and don’t write fraudulent statements.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check out the profiles of current students.&lt;/strong&gt; You can view the Engineering Ambassadors’ profiles here. Take a look at what current students are saying about their programs and their experiences at the University of Waterloo. Their profiles reveal more reasons why Waterloo is so awesome and you can even draw in ideas and inspiration from them. I would highly recommend learning from their responses and somehow incorporating that into your AIF.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Master the fundamentals.&lt;/strong&gt; What I mean by this is make sure your responses are well-written and grammatically correct. When writing your responses, I would recommend saving them on a Word document. The amount of times I’ve heard “OMG, I have to restart my AIF” is ridiculously high. Submit your AIF before the deadline (I recommend even earlier). Be honest, don’t make stuff up. If you get caught, say goodbye to Waterloo.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember who the reader is.&lt;/strong&gt; Too often, people write excellent responses, but they forget their target audience. The main purpose of the AIF is to convince the admission officer that you deserve to be at the University of Waterloo. How can you convince them? First, you have to demonstrate that you’re genuinely interested in studying here (hint: see Part A, question 1). Show them that you’ve done your research about the university and your specific program. Second, you have to prove to them that you would be prepared for co-op job applications. This is where your extracurriculars, employment background, and special awards come in. If you have tons of activities and awards, make sure that you communicate it effectively. If you’re lacking in this department, don’t worry, it’s not too late to get involved. As for filling out the form, you can come up with creative answers that demonstrate your interest in activities outside of school. You can also use the additional 600 character response to write about stuff that you would take on in the future. Lastly, you have to convince them that you have a desire to grow. Keep in mind that the University of Waterloo ranks number one in producing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://uwaterloo.ca/science/news/macleans-ranks-university-waterloo-best-overall-canada&quot;&gt;Leaders of Tomorrow.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After completing the AIF&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proofread your application, it should be flawless.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask your peers, family, and teachers to read over your application.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hope for the best. If you did the best you could do, that’s all that matters at the end of the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the AIF readers don’t have this preconceived notion of what the perfect responses and extracurriculars are. They’re simply looking for applicants who are well-rounded, demonstrate passion and interest in the University of Waterloo, and have the potential to grow. In addition, the applicant must have great communication skills. If your average isn’t the best, a great AIF can potentially get you an admission offer. If you have great marks, the AIF can further optimize your chances. The AIF might even make you a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ugradcalendar.uwaterloo.ca/page/Entrance-Scholarships-and-Awards-for-Engineering&quot;&gt;couple thousand dollars richer.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>End of 1A Reflections</title>
   <link href="bopeng.io///end-of-1a-reflections"/>
   <updated>2014-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>bopeng.io/end-of-1a-reflections</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I know I’ve said this a million times already, but time flies in university. I remember after the second week of school, I was calculating what 2 divided by 13 was in my head. The answer? 15% of the way through 1A. I still find it hard to believe how that was three whole months ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a fair share of good and bad experiences throughout the term (mostly positive ones, but humans tend to focus on the negative events more). Let’s take a stroll down memory lane…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/village1.png&quot; alt=&quot;village one&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-two-months-at-waterloo&quot;&gt;First two months at Waterloo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/residence-move-in-day&quot;&gt;Moving into residence&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/orientation-week-at-waterloo&quot;&gt;orientation week&lt;/a&gt; were amazing life experiences. It’s hard to describe the feeling in words, so you’ll have to trust me on this one. I highly recommend you to participate in these activities! &lt;a href=&quot;/first-month-of-waterloo-engineering&quot;&gt;The first month of Waterloo Engineering&lt;/a&gt; was an incredible experience as well. You can also read about my &lt;a href=&quot;/halfway-through-1a-waterloo-engineering&quot;&gt;midway post.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;engineering-ambassador-and-outreach-events&quot;&gt;Engineering Ambassador and outreach events&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;November was a great month, beginning with the &lt;a href=&quot;/waterloo-open-house-fall-2014&quot;&gt;Waterloo Fall Open House.&lt;/a&gt; I enjoyed talking with prospective students and answering their questions. The most common question was “What’s the difference between Computer Science, Software Engineering, and Computer Engineering?” I’ll probably write a post about this in the future when I gain more experiences. For the meanwhile, check out Patrick Lam’s well written responses comparing the three programs. &lt;a href=&quot;https://uwaterloo.ca/software-engineering/future-undergraduate-students/comparing-bse-bcs&quot;&gt;Comparing SE vs. CS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://uwaterloo.ca/software-engineering/future-undergraduate-students/comparing-bse-basc-comp-eng&quot;&gt;Comparing SE vs. CE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also took on other initiatives as an Engineering Ambassador. I gave out three shadow days, where prospective students shadowed me for the entire day. The three students not only learned more about Waterloo, but also had lots of fun! I would highly recommend the &lt;a href=&quot;https://uwaterloo.ca/engineering-student-ambassadors/shadow-program&quot;&gt;Waterloo Engineering Shadow Program&lt;/a&gt; to any prospective Engineering student. In addition, I volunteered at a Waterloo Alumni event at the Oakville Conference Centre. Three other related achievements I was proud of were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;https://yconic.com/discussion/waterloo-engineering-admission-2015/t44500&quot;&gt;‘Waterloo Engineering Admissions’ thread&lt;/a&gt; on the StudentAwards forum became the most viewed post on the STEM sub-forum, receiving over 300 responses and 75,000 views.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Professor Bill Anderson gave my blog &lt;a href=&quot;https://profbillanderson.wordpress.com/2014/10/09/first-month-of-waterloo-engineering-bo-pengs-world/&quot;&gt;a shout out&lt;/a&gt;. This was an incredible feeling because I followed his blog throughout high school. It definitely helped me out with the admissions process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m now featured on Waterloo’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://uwaterloo.ca/find-out-more/student-life/student-blogs&quot;&gt;first-year blogger website&lt;/a&gt;. Initially, my name was spelled as ‘Po Beng’ which was surprisingly amusing. :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m quite satisfied with what I’ve accomplished as an Engineering Ambassador over the past term, but I know there is always room to improve. One project I would like to take on next term is to organize school field trips to the University of Waterloo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/volunteer-alumni.png&quot; alt=&quot;Volunteer Alumni Event&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;extracurriculars-enactus--engineering-society&quot;&gt;Extracurriculars: Enactus &amp;amp; Engineering Society&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our executive team planned a successful kick-off meeting on November 11th. Check out the photos on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/79155431@N08/sets/72157647155979824/&quot;&gt;Flickr!&lt;/a&gt; We invited our Faculty Advisor, David, our Enactus Canada manager, Julie, Enactus Laurier President, Thomas, and AISEC Waterloo President, Nima to speak. The atmosphere in the room was great and you could instantly tell that the 50+ people who attended were excited! We planned two more meetings after that and have an official team size of 50 members. We’ll be kicking off 2015 with our innovative social projects! We’re looking forward to the National Competition in May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was one of the two EngSoc representatives for my class and had a great time throughout the term. I attended 6 meetings, and many more EngSoc events. It’s absolutely amazing to see how much passion the executives and the other class reps have for the love of Engineering at Waterloo. From charity pancakes to volunteering at the Museum to the semi-formal, there are always fun events planned. Did I mention that there was free food at every single meeting? Another event I particularly enjoyed was the Career Fair that the VP of Education, Josh, organized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/enactus-team-fall-2014.png&quot; alt=&quot;Enactus Team Photo Fall 2014&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;se-hack-day-and-nspire-start-up-competition&quot;&gt;SE Hack Day and Nspire Start-Up Competition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SE Hack day is an event held every term, where students work on a project for 6-8 hours. My friends and I created a Waterloo Food Menu app, which displays the restaurant locations and times, weekly menus, and even allows you to check your remaining meal plan balance. We didn’t quite finish it; however, it was a really chill night filled with learning and fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also participated in a 24 Hour Start-Up competition which actually spanned the entire weekend, from Friday night to Sunday. My team created an app called “CityKit”. Through the CityKit application, users are connected with relevant events based on their location and time, effortlessly while on-the-go. Our service also empowers economic development within cities all around the world. It provides businesses and entrepreneurs with a simple yet effective platform that showcases their events and products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/nspire-hack.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nspire team&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought of this idea after being unaware of a Santa Claus parade occurring in the city. Ultimately, this led in the King Street being blocked out and causing major inconveniences to the traffic. If we had the CityKit app, we would have known about this parade and either arranged alternate travel plans or maybe even attend this festive event. We find that people are often too disconnected with what is occurring in the city, and more focused on what is going on in only their lives. We want people to become urban adventurers and integrate the city into their lives. Admittedly, it’s an ambitious goal, but we’ll see how this goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;academics-and-final-exams&quot;&gt;Academics and Final Exams&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1A was quite an interesting experience in terms of academics. I think I performed at a decent level for the term. I will find out my marks on December 22nd; however, I already know that I was not satisfied with my performance this term. With hindsight, there are so many things that I can improve on. These include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Starting assignments the day they’re assigned rather than the day they’re due.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t skip lectures and don’t fall behind.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare for midterms and finals in advance, instead of the night before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that I was quite distracted this term and didn’t put in much effort. Next term, I promise I will change my habits and work hard. I know I have what it takes to become an excellent student. I must add that there are many resources for achieving student success such as your Professor’s office hours, practice exams, hardworking classmates, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;funandcoolstuff&quot;&gt;#FunAndCoolStuff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meeting the Dean of Engineering, Pearl Sullivan and receiving a Dean’s Ducky&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watching Velocity Final Fund Pitches&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sarah Sharp presentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Every Friday night&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;V1 Waffle Station&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engineering awards dinner&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SE Fall 2014 Class Social&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Lafille” - &lt;a href=&quot;http://davepagurek.com/&quot;&gt;Dave Pagurek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watching Big Hero 6 twice in three days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The week where I had free dinner every single night&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The span of 4 days where I played ping pong more than I slept (the amount of times I’ve heard random people say: “Hey I saw you playing pingpong at V1”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/deans-ducky.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dean&#39;s Ducky&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list goes on and on… To say that I’m having a great time at Waterloo would be an understatement. I am truly having the time of my life. It’s been one heck of a term, and I’m glad it’s finally over. I’m looking forward to spending a nice Winter Break with friends and family. To my classmates and all the friends I’ve made this term, thank you for making my first term such a wonderful experience. To all the professors and TA’s, thank you. To the Software 2018’s, I’m really going to miss you guys. To MC2066 (an extremely hot and uncomfortable lecture room), I cannot say the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ll end this post with a beautiful picture of the glorious Math and Computing building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/mc1.png&quot; alt=&quot;MC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Waterloo Open House Fall 2014</title>
   <link href="bopeng.io///waterloo-open-house-fall-2014"/>
   <updated>2014-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>bopeng.io/waterloo-fall-open-house-2014</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An estimated total of over 11,000 people attended Waterloo’s Fall Open House 2014. This represents a new record, and it just astonishes me how much Waterloo grows every single year. I volunteered for the entire day as the department lead ambassador for Software Engineering, so it’s very likely that I met many of my readers in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fall-open-house.png&quot; alt=&quot;fall open house 2014&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember how one year ago, I was the person asking the volunteers questions. Times have changed, and now I’m the  one who answers these questions and share my experience at Waterloo. I really enjoyed meeting so many passionate students and sharing my personal stories with them. Andrew Morton, the director of the Software Engineering program, gave a very informational presentation about our program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the room was always packed and boiling hot, each person learned something new about our program and had their questions addressed. At the end of every presentation, a few upper-year students and I would hold an open question and answer session for the whole crowd. I think having the current students talk about their experiences and answering the questions was a great supplement to the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, thanks to everyone who came out today! The Fall Open House was a huge success!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Halfway Through 1A Waterloo Engineering</title>
   <link href="bopeng.io///halfway-through-1a-waterloo-engineering"/>
   <updated>2014-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>bopeng.io/halfway-through-1a-waterloo-engineering</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! Sorry that I haven’t posted anything in the past month. School and life has been extraordinarily busy! Remember when I mentioned how time flies? Well, it’s exactly how my life is right now. It feels as if the beginning of October was just yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the highlights of my second month at Waterloo Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignments-labs-and-quizzes&quot;&gt;Assignments, labs and, quizzes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our five core courses, we have weekly assignments, labs, and quizzes. Assignments are either done on paper or through online assessments. Some of them are quite challenging and tricky; however, each one is only worth 1%. Quizzes are written during tutorials and test your understanding of the concepts. They’re usually only worth 1% each as well. As you can tell, assignments and quizzes make up only a small portion of your overall mark. This doesn’t mean you should fool around and not take them seriously. They are important because they test your knowledge and understanding of concepts, before the major midterm and final exams. If you’re doing poorly on them, you should immediately seek help and review your studying habits. Since there’s assignments, labs, and quizzes every single week, it always keep you busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;midterm-week&quot;&gt;Midterm week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Tuesday October 14th to Saturday October 18th, I had 5 midterm exams. Thankfully, we didn’t have any classes during this week. I personally thought that the midterms were quite representative of what we learned in class. The questions were all very fair. I don’t want to dwell into too many details, but I learned a lot during midterm week. I will definitely prepare and study harder for the final exams. As long as you maintain a strong work ethic and do the practice midterms, you’ll do well. I’m looking forward to the final exams in December, which is spread over two weeks. Hopefully, I can learn from my past mistakes and improve my final marks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scribbler-project&quot;&gt;Scribbler Project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our Software Engineering 101 course, we are required to program a robot to perform certain features. It’s an interesting project; however, it’s super difficult to operate the Scribbler smoothly. There’s so many issues wrong with it such as high dependance on battery level, poor censors, and glitchy motors. My group recently demoed our bot for the Object Avoidance test. It seems like a simple task, but all of the previously mentioned problems makes it a pain to work with. Our next step is to program the Scribbler bot to perform any desired function. Our group’s idea is to make the robot follow different paths and then play the appropriate music notes. We will be using key features such as line following and colour recognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;engineering-society-events&quot;&gt;Engineering Society Events&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes Waterloo’s Engineering Society so awesome is the fact that they run so many events throughout the year. In October, there were some really fun events such as: Coffee House at Bomber, charity pancakes, hockey night, First Year Mentoring Conference, Middle of Term party, Women in Engineering Yoga, pumpkin carving, all nighters, costume contest, programming workshop, Change4Change, and the list just goes on and on. I would highly recommend everyone to get involved with EngSoc because not only are the events incredibly fun, but you also build upon your soft skills and get to meet new people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enactus-waterloo&quot;&gt;Enactus Waterloo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh man, running Enactus Waterloo has eaten up so much of my time. I briefly discussed about my involvement with Enactus Waterloo in my previous blog post. Our core executive team met several times and brainstormed about project ideas. Now that I think about it, coming up with a brilliant idea and executing it is quite challenging. We also launched a recruitment campaign for the executive positions. We used social media and word of mouth to spread the news. By the end of the week, we received almost double the number of applications that we had initially expected. I was quite impressed by the applicants’ qualifications, willingness to learn, and most importantly their passion for social entrepreneurship. However, choosing the applicants for an interview was not an easy process. There were so many qualified applicants, but our team can only afford so much time to interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past week, I was at Tim Horton’s interviewing applicants every single day from 6:00pm to 8:00pm, with some additional interviews in the morning and afternoon. I must say it was quite an interesting experience being on the other side of the table. As the interviewer, you really get to know each candidate on a personal level. I particularly enjoyed listening to each applicant’s unique story and their passion for changing the world. There were many tough decisions to make, but I’m glad the stressful selection process is all over (for now).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Waterloo has a co-op program, students typically alternate between school and work terms. This makes choosing the executive team an even trickier decision because people come and go every four months. Therefore, we decided to recruit two sets of alternating executives. We are very happy with our newly selected executives and anticipate it’s going to be one heck of a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s what happened in the month of October. I still can’t believe I’m halfway through my 1A term. To be honest, time is flying way too quickly, I wish I could just slow down the clock. Oh wait, tonight is the end of Daylight savings time, so we’ll have to turn back the clock by an hour. Awesome, I guess my wish just got granted! Anyways, until next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First Month of Waterloo Engineering</title>
   <link href="bopeng.io///first-month-of-waterloo-engineering"/>
   <updated>2014-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>bopeng.io/first-month-of-waterloo-engineering</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Oh man, it’s October already? Time really does fly in university…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first month in university was incredible. Without a doubt, it was one of the best months of my life. You guys are probably wondering right now: “Bo, what made your month so special?” My response would be: “Everything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;academics&quot;&gt;Academics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing’s first, we go to university to learn and indulge in the world of academics. I’m studying Software Engineering, one of the most competitive and rigorous programs in Canada. I am taking six courses: linear algebra, calculus, linear circuits, physics, computer science and a Software Engineering course. This approximates to about 30 hours of class each week. I’ve attached my schedule below, and you can see that from Monday-Thursday I have class from 8:30AM-6:00PM. On Friday, it’s only 8:30AM-1:30PM. The blue represent my lectures, tutorials, labs and seminars. The purple represent due dates, office hours, and other miscellaneous events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/engineering-schedule.png&quot; alt=&quot;engineering schedule&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In each course, we either have weekly assignments, quizzes, labs, or a combination of the above. Fortunately, they’re only worth up to 20% of your mark, so doing poorly on one of them won’t kill your mark. They definitely teach you to properly manage your time and prepare you for the big midterm and final exams. As you can imagine, waking up to morning classes every single day is quite tiring. It’s important to get as much sleep as you can, but sometimes it’s quite difficult (unless you have a great work ethic). It’s essential to review your notes and do the assignments to ensure a good understanding of concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I started off the year with a poor work ethic, worrying more about my social life than homework. I have slowly been improving my work ethic and have almost caught up! Falling behind in a course is NOT recommended. My advice is to finish your assignments and work well before they are due. DO NOT start your assignment the night before it’s due. Speaking from my personal experience, it’s a horrible idea. This isn’t high school anymore, where you can breeze through homework and assignments in under an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In first-year engineering, students have this week called “Hell Week”, where they have an entire week dedicated for midterms. I don’t have any classes during this week, but the thought of having 5 midterm exams in 5 days is quite intimidating. For the next two weeks, I’m going to be working super hard to get the best marks I can. Hopefully, when I blog about my midterms in two weeks from now, I’ll be in a happy mood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;extracurriculars&quot;&gt;Extracurriculars&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I LOVE extracurriculars and doing stuff outside of the classroom. Actually, I think I like them a bit too much because they’re eating up a big chunk of my time. In high school, I was involved in this awesome club called “SAGE (Students for the Advancement of Global Entrepreneurship.” Basically, students team up to create and implement entrepreneurial projects that addresses a social problem within the community. Joining SAGE was probably one of the best decisions I made in high school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of my involvement with SAGE, I decided to start and lead an Enactus chapter at Waterloo. The logistics involved with starting a club was quite time consuming, but we are now officially a registered club at the University of Waterloo and are affiliated with Enactus Canada. We managed to find an incredible and experienced Faculty Advisor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of our club is to utilize the power of social entrepreneurship to transform lives and shape a better world. We will create and implement community projects that empower the lives of individuals to improve their standard of living and quality of life. We will present our projects at the Enactus regional and national competitions where we will be evaluated by global leaders and executives serving as judges. Club members will have the opportunity to attend conferences, competitions, and workshops to enhance their professional development. I will start recruiting members and executives after my “Hell Week” ends. Enactus Waterloo is going to be one heck of a ride!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to starting my own club, I’m involved in a bunch of other clubs. I was elected to be the Engineering Society representative of my Software Engineering class. Check out our class’s website. I’ve only attended two meetings so far, but I can confidently say EngSoc meetings are hilarious! I am going to be attending their events on a regular basis and also volunteer for them. In the future, I’m looking forward to obtaining director and executive roles in Engineering Society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also a Waterloo Engineering Ambassador. I would recommend checking out the Waterloo Engineering Shadow Program. You’ll get to experience a day-in-the-life of an Engineering student! I went on two shadow days last year, and it was two great learning experiences. As an Engineering Ambassador now, it feels like a full circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;social-life&quot;&gt;Social Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many stories. Too many awesome moments. I’m compiling a big list of memorable moments at Waterloo and it’s quite long already. I’ll definitely share some of these moments with you guys later. I just want to make it clear that Waterloo is not anti-social. To be more exact, no place is anti-social, it all depends on the person. Let’s just say that I’ve partied at least once every single weekend and that they’re EPICLY FUN. I would say that my social life is superb right now, and I’m having the time of my life. I’m going to have to sacrifice some aspects of my social life over the next two weeks to focus on exams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sleep&quot;&gt;Sleep&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The magic number is 49. How did I get that number? 7 days * 7 hours per day. You should aim for that many hours of sleep each week. Personally, I’m falling a bit under 49 hours/ week of sleep due to academics and social life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fun-fact&quot;&gt;Fun fact.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was one week where I got free dinner every single night. How did I pull this off?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Club meetings, employer info sessions, tech talks always have free food!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First Week of Classes</title>
   <link href="bopeng.io///first-week-of-classes"/>
   <updated>2014-09-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>bopeng.io/first-week-of-classes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hey there everyone! It’s been quite a hectic first two weeks at Waterloo. When I say hectic, I mean THE BEST TIME EVER!!! Although my schedule is packed, I’m going to try my best to write weekly posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s a recap of my first week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday was the first day of class of my university career. I woke up quite late, so I barely made it to class on time. It sort of felt like the first day of high school when I was looking for an open seat. Except this time, I actually knew tons of people in my program beforehand. The professor “Mario” wasted no time in starting the MATH 115 (Linear Algebra for Engineers) lecture. It was really difficult to take notes and maintain focus at the back, so a couple of us went directly to the front and sat down on the ground. Next thing you know, the 50 minute lecture was over. We had an hour break until our next class, so we went to the SLC and chatted with our classmates. My classmates are pretty awesome people and I know I’m going to have a blast with them over the next five years. We’ll have our glorious moments together and also have those times of struggles. However, the one thing I dislike most about my classmates is the fact that we’re all super keeners who line up at the door 20 minutes before the class starts. Don’t expect a good seat if you arrive 10 minutes early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, we had three consecutive lectures: MATH117 (Calculus), ECE105 (Physics), and ECE140 (Linear Circuits). These courses along with CS137 (Computer Science) and SE101 (Software Engineering  Course) seem pretty interesting at first glance — much better than the high school courses we were forced to take. I know I’m going to have to build a strong work ethic in order to thrive in this rigorous program. I’ll write an update post on these 6 courses in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the week was similar to Monday, tons of lectures and academics. I won’t comment too much about them because they’re quite boring!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, my classmates and I discovered the Software Engineering lounge. It’s so cool that it needs a password to get in. The lounge has very comfy couches and even has a refrigerator. Several “softies” chilled in the room and socialized. I recall some of the guys karaokeing to ‘Bohemian Rhapsody’ by Queen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday was special because there was a ‘Super Mega Software Class Get Together.’ There was a student from all 5 current Software classes at Waterloo. To sum up, it was a really nice event to get to know your classmates and upper-year students They provided us with fantastic advice and of course scared us a little bit. The Associate Director of Software Engineering even attended the event. A couple of people actually thought he was a student! With hindsight, I shouldn’t have eaten the whole box of Oreos. (The Freshman Fifteen is real.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday there was Resume Critiques hosted by the Waterloo Engineering Society. I didn’t go because I wasn’t feeling too well and the line was too long. From what I’ve heard, it was a great and very helpful event. I will make sure to attend the next Resume Critique!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hands down, Friday was the best day of the week for numerous reasons. First, Friday is my lightest day with classes from 8:30 to 1:30pm. Second, there was a Software Engineering frisbee game between many 2018 softies and first years. Playing sports, especially team sports, with others is a fantastic way to bond. I’m definitely going to keep in touch with many of the people I played with. Perhaps, another frisbee game in the future? It was difficult to distinguish which player was on which team, so we played a “Skins vs Shirts” game. I was part of the “skins” team. Oh man, it was cold… But I have no regrets, since it was an awesome game!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the game, I took a nice, refreshing shower and got ready for Engineering Society’s Beginning of Term party at POETS. The party wasn’t the type of party I expected, but I still had a great time meeting and talking with other students. Hmm, I wonder if I could list that under my interests for my resume. “I love meeting new people and listening to their stories.” There were plenty of snacks and drinks, which is always a plus for any event. The upper-years who only talked with other upper-years were sprayed with water by EngSoc directors! Finally, the recurring theme of “sense of community” within Software Engineering appeared once again. Every single Software Engineering student I’ve met have all been super incredible and friendly people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to coming here, I had high expectations for Waterloo. So far, this experience at Waterloo has far exceeded my previous expectations. What more can I say? I love Waterloo.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Rain Never Bothered Me Anyway</title>
   <link href="bopeng.io///the-rain-never-bothered-me-anyway"/>
   <updated>2014-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>bopeng.io/the-rain-never-bothered-me-anyway</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s some things in this world you just can’t control. One of them is &lt;strong&gt;rain.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past week, it has rained numerous times in Waterloo. As a result, many orientation events were modified or cancelled. This obviously sucked for all of the enthusiastic froshies like me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HOWEVER…. orientation week was still a blast! Everyone kept a positive attitude and looked past the miserable weather. What made the week so fun was the awesome people I met. These people are going to be my future best friends, classmates, co-workers, significant others, or perhaps even future boss!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’m trying to say is that you should always be an optimistic person and make the most out of unfortunate situations. Always try to maintain a positive attitude and have fun! Check out Shawn Achor’s TED Talk on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fLJsdqxnZb0&quot;&gt;Happy Secret to Better Work.&lt;/a&gt; He explains how changing your view of the world and life to a more positive one can increase both your happiness and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a quote from one of my favourite movies of all time, Rocky Balboa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The world ain’t all sunshine and rainbows. It’s a very mean and nasty place and I don’t care how tough you are it will beat you to your knees and keep you there permanently if you let it. You, me, or nobody is gonna hit as hard as life. But it ain’t about how hard you hit. It’s about how hard you can get hit and keep moving forward. How much you can take and keep moving forward. That’s how winning is done! Now if you know what you’re worth then go out and get what you’re worth. But ya gotta be willing to take the hits, and not pointing fingers saying you ain’t where you wanna be because of him, or her, or anybody! Cowards do that and that ain’t you!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Rocky famously conveys, you should NOT blame others for your problems. Rather than complain about them, you should simply accept that there are matters in life which you can’t control. I, too, have went through difficult times in my life. It took a while for me to realize, but complaining and blaming others doesn’t help. It only makes the situation even worse. What you can and should do is filter the negative things in your life and convert them into motivation. Push yourself to work even harder, and never stop persevering. Remember life WILL get better. By putting yourself in an optimistic state, you’re in a good position to achieve happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Orientation Week at Waterloo</title>
   <link href="bopeng.io///orientation-week-at-waterloo"/>
   <updated>2014-09-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>bopeng.io/orientation-week-at-waterloo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Today is day 6 of my Waterloo experience! Here’s a recap of my journey so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 1:&lt;/strong&gt; I moved in to Village One on Sunday. The official move in day for my building was on Monday, so it was just me and another guy for the whole day. Moving in and saying goodbye to my parents was quite bittersweet. I’m going to miss living with them, but I’m also going to enjoy every single moment of this new lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I participated in the scheduled orientation activities: Warrior Welcome and Playfair. Warrior Welcome was decent. It was basically a pep rally event trying to create Waterloo spirit. Playfair was surprisingly really fun. There were about two thousand first year students doing fun activities on the V1 Green. Some activities were really awkward, but that’s what makes it so fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 2:&lt;/strong&gt; My floor mates moved in on Monday (which woke me up urgh). They are really nice people! I’m looking forward to living with them for the next 8 months. Our building had a introduction meeting and played icebreakers to get to know each other. I recall playing a LOT of ping pong on this day. Aside from that, nothing interesting happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 3:&lt;/strong&gt; Tuesday was the first day of the orientation week activities. Since I’m in Software Engineering, I get to participate in both the Math and Engineering orientation activities. I was part of team Dark-Yellow in Engineering and Meme-Theorem Valley in Math. The day started off at the Dark-Yellow(“dellow”) headquarters. I met a lot of new and fascinating people from my team. The leaders, especially the Software people, were awesome people. Next up was a speech from the Dean of Engineering at Waterloo, Pearl Sullivan. She’s an extraordinary person and definitely embodies Waterloo’s values and culture. Out of nowhere, Edcom pops up and sends a message to all the Frosh. I’m not going to describe edcom because I don’t want to give any spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, the Software kids from my group went to the Math Orientation team. We met up in Davis Centre and did a couple of sub-par activities. They were pretty lame to be honest. Whatever, at least I got the opportunity to meet new people. The day was filled with rain, so the orientation activities for Engineering had to be modified. Regardless, we still got our coveted Yellow Hardhat at the end of the day. During the night, I hung out with friends and checked out  “Choose your own adventure”. There were activities planned such as Haunted House, hypnotist show, drag show, and much more. We had to wait an hour and a half to get in the two minute Haunted House. I would say it’s not worth it, but I loved bonding with the others during the long wait time. Apparently, the hypnotist show was epic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 4:&lt;/strong&gt; All Engineering students had Wednesday off, except the Software kids. I went to the Software Engineering 101 event and then had a department lunch at Mongolian grill. The food was amazing. The people were even more incredible. Then, we participated in various activities to earn our Pink Tie. During the night time, my friends and I participated in World of Waterloo, which was basically a tour of the city of Waterloo. It was decent, but was way too hyped up. Afterwards, a couple of us went to Chatime (never a bad time for Chatime).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 5:&lt;/strong&gt; Thursday was a SUPER FUN day. The 1500+ first-year Engineering students participated in the aerial photo at St. Paul green. I’m excited to see how the picture will turn out. This type of stuff requires so much organization and creativity! Next, the 16 teams battled against each other in the Junkyard Wars. I don’t want to spoil this either, but let’s say a lot of collaboration and quick thinking is required. The highlight of the orientation activities was definitely the “Single and Sexy” play. It exceeded my expectations and made the entire audience go into laughter. Of course, there were also key lessons portrayed. If you’re going to Waterloo next year, you MUST watch this. It’s THAT good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also the Monte Carlo, which started at 8:00 PM. Most people dressed up in a semi-formal way. I was impressed by how much effort people put into dressing up. The event was hosted at SLC, and was actually fun. There were a bunch of casino games set up. The Texas Hold ‘Em tables were super filled up. What I loved most about the event was the complimentary snacks! I left Monte Carlo early and then went to Frosh Frenzy at Pearl nightclub with my friends. I’m not going to disclose the specific details about Frosh Frenzy because I have a wide audience of people reading my blog. Let’s just say there was a lot of dancing and cheering. It was definitely one of the best nights ever. Well worth the money spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 6:&lt;/strong&gt; There was a huge thunderstorm in Waterloo Friday morning, with some of the loudest thunder cracks and powerful lightning strikes I’ve ever witnessed. It was reported that a female student from the University of Waterloo was struck by lightning and later passed away in the hospital. It’s such a tragic event.  I’d like to send all of my condolences to the student and her family. This event really got me thinking about life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Safety should always be prioritized.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;You never know when your last day will be so enjoy every single moment. Life is simply too short to be depressed all the time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll conclude this post with an interesting graphic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/orientation-week-graphic.png&quot; alt=&quot;orientation week&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past week, I’ve lived by this quote. I haven’t had much sleep, but who cares? ‘Cause I’m having so much fun, and this is probably the last time in a long time, where I can afford to give up sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quick Stats Software Engineering Class of 2019</title>
   <link href="bopeng.io///quick-stats-software-engineering-2019"/>
   <updated>2014-09-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>bopeng.io/quick-stats-software-engineering-2019</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The program director, Andrew Morton, revealed some stats about this year’s Software Engineering students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enrolled/Applied:&lt;/strong&gt; 140 students vs 640 applicants&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;# of females:&lt;/strong&gt; 24 students (17% overall, tied for highest ever)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall average:&lt;/strong&gt; 94%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cutoff average:&lt;/strong&gt; ~90% This number is calculated by averaging the applicants with bottom 10% admission averages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;# Enrolled 2018 class:&lt;/strong&gt; 151 students, so this year 11 less people were enrolled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 class 1B co-op employment rate:&lt;/strong&gt; 99.3%&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>University Application Important Dates</title>
   <link href="bopeng.io///university-application-important-dates"/>
   <updated>2014-08-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>bopeng.io/university-application-important-dates</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I start my first day of university tomorrow, I’d like to share with you grade 12’s the process of applying to university. This post will be a brief timeline and will only contain information about Ontario universities. I didn’t apply to Out of Province universities so I’m not knowledgable about that. By the way, I went to a semestered school in Ontario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ouac.png&quot; alt=&quot;university application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;timeline&quot;&gt;Timeline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 2014&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ontario University Fair (OUF): The OUF is running from September 19th to 21st this year at the Metro Toronto Convention Centre. All universities in Ontario will be there! They typically will bring admission officers, recruitment/marketing officers, undergrad students and professors. Make sure you come prepared with questions. If not, don’t worry because they’re all really friendly people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2014&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parent-Teacher night: To be honest, this night isn’t very important. However, by this date, your teachers should provide you with a mark update. If you’re doing well, keep up the good work! Make sure you don’t lose momentum and slack off. If you’re doing “meh”, then this is the time you have to start working even harder. If you’re doing poorly, this is your wake up call. These next few months determine the rest of your life. So why waste this opportunity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halloween: HAVE FUN! Remember grade 12 is supposed to be the fun year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;University fall open house: These typically run in late October and early November. You can drive to your desired school and check out their campus. This is very useful for checking the culture, both academic and social.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pro tip: If you’re interested in Waterloo Engineering, definitely apply for a shadow day. I participated in one last year and I really enjoyed it. It’s basically a one-on-one tour with a Waterloo Engineering student!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 2014&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Semester 1 midterm marks: You’re getting closer and closer to the end of Semester 1 (or midterms for those non-semesters kids). Basically follow the same advice I gave for Parent-Teacher night. This set of marks are NOT reported to Ontario universities. So you have some breathing room, if your marks aren’t what you’d like to them to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OUAC Pins handed out: Around mid-late November (sometimes even early December), your school will hand out your Ontario University Application Centre pins. Now you can start applying to University! YAY! You can browse through your programs and then apply. Applying is very simple. All you have to do is choose your programs and then pay. You have to pay $130 for your first 3 programs, and then additional $44 for each program beyond the initial 3. Note: You must pay $130, even if you apply to one university. You will be able to see all of you grade 11 courses under academic information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 2014&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week before Winter break: For some reason, everyone tends to slack off this time of year. (I did too) Make sure you keep doing your homework and maintain your work ethic, otherwise it’ll cost you a couple of % on your final mark. Just hang in there for a bit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winter break: During the break, I would strongly recommend to work on your supplementary application. Most competitive programs require a supplementary application. Generally, you have to write a few short essay responses and list your extracurricular activities. At Waterloo, if you don’t fill out the AIF, you may not be considered for admission. Make sure when you’re done to have a peer or teacher edit it. The supplementary is important for both admission and scholarship purposes. I will cover this in another post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 2015&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back from break: So you’re back from the break. You have about 3-4 weeks, until semester one is done. Keep on working hard and prepare well for the exams. If it comes down to a shortage of time, focus on your program’s required courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Super-early admission offers: Some universities will hand out super-early admission offers to students with amazing grade 11 marks (or grade 12 if they fast tracked) in December/January. Don’t be concerned if you don’t receive an offer at this time. Some programs don’t even hand out offers during this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 2015&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supplementary application deadlines: Most apps are due in February, some are due a bit later. Submit them! Don’t wait until the last minute to do them. Please, I can’t stress this enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Semester 1 final marks uploaded on OUAC: Your school will report your marks to OUAC and universities will be able to see them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early admission offers: Many programs will hand out offers during late February/early March based on your Semester 1 final marks. They typically hand out a small portion of their offers. For example, Waterloo Engineering only handed out roughly a quarter to a third of their offers during the early round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March 2015&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March open house: Same thing as above, check them out if you’re interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuous round of offers: Some programs hand out continuous offers throughout March and April. Waterloo Engineering does this for out of province students. If you’re an Ontario student, don’t expect an offer during this time span.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 2015&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Semester 2 midterm marks: In mid-late April, semester 2 midterm marks will be up on OUAC. By this point, you’ve done all you could to help your cause. Now, your fate is in the hands of the admission officers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 2015&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge round of offers (“regular admission”): This is pretty much the final and largest round of offers. Universities will hand out the offers they have left. If you received an offer, CONGRATULATIONS! If not, then oh well, you tried your best right? If you still want to get in the program, I suggest you apply to be on the wait list. There’s also another type of offer- alternate offer. If your application was not strong enough for the program you applied to, universities sometimes give you an alternate offer to a less competitive program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prom: Have fun. You’ve waited the whole year for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 2015&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deadline to accept your offer on OUAC: Last year was June 2nd, this year I think it’s June 1st. Accept your offer! It might be hard choosing between two or more programs, but follow your heart. Don’t make anyone else make that decision for you. Speak to your teachers, family, university alumni, and etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply to OSAP: If you require funding for your studies, definitely apply to OSAP. I might post a detailed guide on this some other day. Listen to me when I say this: don’t procrastinate on this. It might seem like work, but remember, this is money you’re dealing with. I recommend you guys to apply before June 15th. You’ll get funding estimates earlier and if you made a mistake, you can fix it earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintain your conditional offer: All universities hand out conditional offers. This means that you have to keep a specific mark in your pre-req’s and top 6 average, or some variant of this. Usually the conditional averages they require are tens of % below your admission average. However, make sure you don’t cross below the threshold. Your offer may be at risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait list: Sometimes, if you’re in the right place at the right time, you can get off the wait list and receive a late offer to your desired university program! Don’t bank on this though. I’m just throwing the idea out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I have covered the basics of the university application timeline. If you prepare well, it won’t be that stressful. Anyways, good luck on your grade 12 year!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Residence Move In Day</title>
   <link href="bopeng.io///residence-move-in-day"/>
   <updated>2014-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>bopeng.io/residence-move-in-day</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s 7:00am and right now I’m in the car leaving off to Waterloo. I will be living in a single room in Village 1. I will cover the topic of residences in a future post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been preparing myself for move in day for months now. I’m still astonished by how fast semester 2 and the summer went. Of course, there were some moments that went incredibly slow (cramming for Chemistry tests, procrastinating on English essays, preparing for interviews, etc.) I don’t normally get this hyped for an event but this is the university life we’re talking about. My expectations of Waterloo are probably way too high right now. I’m sure it won’t disappoint as long as I make an effort to enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be precise, my official move in day is tomorrow (September 1st) but I requested to move in earlier due to a scheduling conflict. I hope there will be at least one person in my residence today. Nevertheless, I am excited to meet everyone from my floor and building tomorrow. I’ll probably roam around Waterloo tonight and hang out with my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I’m almost at Waterloo. It’s going to be bittersweet saying goodbye to my parents in a few hours. Oh well, c’est la vie.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello World!</title>
   <link href="bopeng.io///hello-world"/>
   <updated>2014-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>bopeng.io/hello-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! My name is Bo Peng and I’m a first-year Software Engineering student at the University of Waterloo. I’ll be blogging about my experiences (both good and bad) here. I’ll also post some informational stuff for you keen high schoolers wanting to apply to university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I better get back to packing now… Move in day is tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
